<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  
  <!-- EN: psylink -->
  <PsychicAmplifier.label>łącze PSI</PsychicAmplifier.label>
  <!-- EN: An organic connection to a larger psychic field. This allows a person to psychically induce a distant archotech superintelligence to influence reality in ways that seem impossible.\n\nHigher levels of psylink permit the use of more powers. Regardless of psylink level, a person can only use specific powers that they have learned.\n\nPsylink comes from a variety of sources. Single-use psylink neuroformer devices can create a psylink. Tribal peoples also know how to develop it through ritual linking with the legendary anima tree.\n\nAs a physical phenomenon in the brain, psylink is poorly-understood by scientists, not least because it seems to actively conceal itself if studied too closely. One thing most agree on is that it somehow connects people to archotechs and harnesses their power, possibly through some sort of negotiation or sympathy mechanism. -->
  <PsychicAmplifier.description>Organiczne połączenie z większym polem psychicznym. Pozwala osobie na użycie określonych mocy psychicznych, których wcześniej się nauczyła, które oddziałują na rzeczywistość w sposób, jaki wydaje się niemożliwy.\n\nWiększe poziomy łącza psychicznego pozwalają na użytek większej ilości mocy. Nieważne jaki poziom łącza psychicznego posiada osoba, może ona używać jedynie mocy których się nauczyła.\n\nPsylink można uzyskać z różnych źródeł. Można użyć jednorazowego neuroformera łącza psychicznego. Plemiona znają sposób na uzyskanie go poprzez rytuał połączenia z psychicznie połączonymi formami życia.\n\nJako fizyczny fenomen w mózgu, łącze psychiczne jest słabo rozumiane przez naukowców, i nie tylko dlatego, że w jakiś sposób ukrywa swoje istnienie podczas dogłębniej obserwacji. Większość zgadza się z jednym, że w jakiś sposób łączy ludzi z istotami archotycznymi i pobiera ich moc, prawdopodobnie przez jakiś rodzaj negocjacji, albo mechanizm sympatii.</PsychicAmplifier.description>
  <!-- EN: Allows a person to psychically-induce an archotech to influence reality in ways that seem impossible. Higher levels of psylink permit the use of more powers. -->
  <PsychicAmplifier.descriptionShort>Pozwala osobie na psychiczne indukowanie archatechnologii, aby wpływać na rzeczywistość w sposób, jaki wydaje się niemożliwy. Wyższe poziomy łącza pozwalają na użycie większej ilości mocy.</PsychicAmplifier.descriptionShort>
  <PsychicAmplifier.labelNoun>łącze PSI</PsychicAmplifier.labelNoun>
  
</LanguageData>