<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  
  <!-- EN: baseliner -->
  <Baseliner.label>baseliner</Baseliner.label>
  <!-- EN: A naturally-evolved human with no major significant genetic modifications. -->
  <Baseliner.description>Naturalny człowiek bez żadnych znaczących modyfikacji genetycznych.</Baseliner.description>
  
  <!-- EN: dirtmole -->
  <Dirtmole.label>kret</Dirtmole.label>
  <!-- EN: With gray skin adapted to artificial light, they thrive in cramped and dark spaces where combat and travel happen over short distances. They are extremely capable at digging or mining tasks. In the open, however, they suffer from a sensitivity to light, slow speed and poor eyesight at distance.\n\nAfter the first tunnel colonies failed due to the stress of confinement, colonization agencies began genetically altering colonists to live without open space or sunlight. This xenotype are known colloquially as dirtmoles. Today, dirtmoles have expanded out of their original tunnel homes and rule many confined spaces in the anthrosphere. They can be found in deep mines, cramped low-tech spacecraft, and teeming by the billions in the dark underlayers of countless urbworlds. -->
  <Dirtmole.description>Posiadający szarą skórę przystosowaną do sztucznego światła, rozwijają się w ciasnych i ciemnych miejscach, gdzie walka i przemieszczanie odbywa się na bardzo krótkich dystansach. Mają niesamowite zdolności górnicze. Na zewnątrz cierpią jednak z powodu wrażliwości na światło, powolnego chodu i słabego wzroku na odległość.\n\nPo tym, jak pierwsze podziemne kolonie nie wypaliły z powodu zbyt dużego stresu z powodu zamknięcia, agencje kolonizacyjne zaczęły modyfikować geny kolonistów by żyli w zamkniętej przestrzeni bez światła. Ten ksenotyp znany jest jako mól. Dzisiaj mole opuściły swoje oryginalne tunele i rządzą wieloma miejsca w płaszczu globu. Można ich znaleźć w podziemnych kopalniach, zakopanych nie-zaawansowanych pojazdach kosmicznych, i przechadzających się w bilionach po ciemnych podwarstwach niezliczonych urbworldów.</Dirtmole.description>
  <!-- EN: With gray skin adapted to artificial light, dirtmoles thrive in cramped and dark spaces where combat and travel happen over short distances. They are naturals at digging and navigating complex tunnel structures. In the open, they suffer from a sensitivity to light, slow speed and poor eyesight at distance. -->
  <Dirtmole.descriptionShort>Posiadajćy szarą skórę przystosowaną do sztucznego światła, mole ziemne rozwijają się w ciasnych i ciemnych miejscach, gdzie walka i przemieszczanie odbywa się na bardzo krótkich dystansach. Naturalne jest dla nich kopanie i nawigowanie po złożonych strukturach tunelowych. Na powiechrzni cierpią z powodu wrażliwości na światło, powolnego chodu i słabego wzroku na odległość.</Dirtmole.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: genie -->
  <Genie.label>konfrater</Genie.label>
  <!-- EN: Designed to be engineers, genies' delicate bones and natural aptitude with machines allow them to manipulate devices with remarkable precision. They are emotionally cold and can follow orders where others might panic. However, they are fragile, and their amplified nerve impulses make them easy to debilitate with relatively little pain. With so much of their brains dedicated to analyzing machines, they lack the neural hardware to analyze emotions, so they sometimes come off as socially inept. Their dead calm makes it even harder for them to relate to what they see as madly-hotheaded baseliner humans.\n\nGenies were engineered thousands of years ago by a long-disbanded space navy to hold engineering positions on large starships. Today, genies still serve as engineers in great cities and fleets, but many can also be found working as lawyers, pilots, and musicians. -->
  <Genie.description>Stworzeni by być inżynierami, ich delikatne kości i naturalna więź z maszynami sprawia, że mogą manipulować różnymi urządzeniami z doskonałą precyzją. Emocjonalnie są bardzo zimni i wykonują rozkazy nawet gdy inni by spanikowali. Niestety, są bardzo delikatni, a ich wzmocnione impulsy nerwowe sprawiają, że nawet słaby ból ich powala. Przeznaczając tak dużo miejsca w mózgu by zrozumieć maszyny, brakuje im miejsca by zrozumieć emocje, więc czasami uchodzą za społecznie nieudolnych. Ich grobowy spokój sprawia, że jeszcze trudniej im odnieść się do tego co widzą.\n\nGenies zostali stworzeni tysiące lat temu przez dawno rozwiązaną marynarkę wojenną, by zaspokoić zapotrzebowanie na inżynierów na okrętach. Dzisiaj wciąż służą jako inżynierowie w wielkich miastach i flotach, ale wiele z nich pracuje także jako prawnicy, piloci i muzycy.</Genie.description>
  <!-- EN: Designed to be engineers, genies have natural aptitude with machines, and are emotionally cold and calm. They are also fragile and vulnerable to pain. Focused on machines, they often come off as socially inept. -->
  <Genie.descriptionShort>Stworzeni by być inżynierami, genies mają naturalną więź z maszynami, ale są emocjonalnie zimni i spokojni. Są bardzo delikatni i wrażliwi na ból. Skupieni na maszynach, czasami uchodzą za społecznie nieudolnych.</Genie.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: highmate -->
  <Highmate.label>powiernik</Highmate.label>
  <!-- EN: Designed companions and concubines with a unique ability to psychically bond with a mate, highmates are empathic, beautiful, cheerful, and talented in social matters. They are also inept at manual tasks, physically weak, and mentally incapable of violence.\n\nOn a few wealthy worlds, highmate xenogerms are commercially available and some people become highmates as a sort of career. However, many societies find them abhorrent, either because they distract people from forming natural families, or because they are humans shaped to serve the pleasures of another. On such worlds they are either reserved as playthings of the powerful, or banned entirely. This particular line of highmate fits the fashions of classical Novaroma, but many other variants exist. -->
  <Highmate.description>Stworzeni towarzysze i konkubiny, z unikalną zdolność do psychicznego łączenia się z drugą osobą. Są empatyczne, piękne, szczęśliwe i utalentowane w sprawach społecznych. Są nieudolne w robotach ręcznych, słabe psychicznie i niezdolne do przemocy.\n\nNa kilku bogatych światach, ich ksenozarodek są dostępne publicznie i niektórzy zostają towarzyszami by zrobić jakby karierę. Jednak wiele społeczeństw uznaje je za niepotrzebne, choćby dlatego, że odwracają uwagę ludzi od tworzenia normalnych rodzin, albo ponieważ są to ludzie stworzeni w celu zaspokajania fantazji innych. Zależnie od świata są oni zabawkami bogatych, albo są zakazani całkowicie. Ta szczególna linia towarzyszy wpisuje się w definicję klasycznej Novaromy, ale istnieje wiele innych wariantów.</Highmate.description>
  <!-- EN: Designed companions and concubines with a unique ability to psychically bond with a mate, highmates are empathic, beautiful, cheerful, and talented in social matters. They are also inept at manual tasks, physically weak, and mentally incapable of violence. -->
  <Highmate.descriptionShort>Stworzeni towarzysze i konkubiny, z unikalną zdolność do psychicznego łączenia się z drugą osobą. Są empatyczne, piękne, szczęśliwe i utalentowane w sprawach społecznych. Są nieudolne w robotach ręcznych, słabe psychicznie i niezdolne do przemocy.</Highmate.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: hussar -->
  <Hussar.label>husarz</Hussar.label>
  <!-- EN: Hussars are engineered soldiers. They fight aggressively and with precision, heal fast, thrive in extreme temperatures, and freely ingest military drugs. They have a genetic dependence on go-juice, which also makes them less likely to rebel against their commanders.\n\nWhile hussars' emotions make them dangerous in combat, they can't relate to baseliner humans. They are famous for their blood-red eyes and "hussar stare", a dead expression that unsettles many people. Their lack of expression and burning aggressive nature has led to many violent misunderstandings.\n\nIn most societies where they live, hussars are kept separated from the rest of the population. Hussars are single-purpose tools - and they generally aren't bothered by the fact. -->
  <Hussar.description>Husarze to stworzeni żołnierze. Walczą bardzo agresywnie z dużą precyzją, szybko się regenerują, rozwijają w wysokich temperaturach, i bez problemu spożywają wojskowe wspomagacze. Mają genetyczne zapotrzebowanie na sok-go, który zmniejsza prawdopodobieństwo rebelii przeciw przywódcom.\n\nPodczas gdy ich emocje sprawiają, że są niebezpieczni w walce, nie mogą odnieść się do baselinerów. Są znani ze swoich krwisto czerwonych oczu i "spojrzenia husarza", martwego spojrzenia powodującego strach u ludzi. Ich brak ekspresji i płonąca agresywna natura doprowadziły do wielu nieporozumień.\n\nW większości społeczności gdzie żyją, husarze są trzymani z dala od reszty. Husarze mają tylko jeden cel - i raczej im to nie przeszkadza.</Hussar.description>
  <!-- EN: Hussars are engineered soldiers. They fight aggressively and with precision, heal fast, thrive in extreme temperatures, and freely ingest military drugs. They have a genetic dependence on go-juice. -->
  <Hussar.descriptionShort>Husarze to stworzeni żołnierze. Walczą bardzo agresywnie z dużą precyzją, szybko się regenerują, rozwijają w wysokich temperaturach, i bez problemu spożywają wojskowe wspomagacze. Mają genetyczne zapotrzebowanie na sok-go</Hussar.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: impid -->
  <Impid.label>impid</Impid.label>
  <!-- EN: Made for desert life, impid cultures live on many rimworlds and dry deathworlds. Impids are extremely fast-moving, easily tolerate high temperatures, and can spew fire from their mouths. Though they are masters on the sand, impids struggle in other environments. They are terrible with farming. They fight well at range, but in close combat their physical weakness becomes apparent.\n\nOutlanders call them dustrunners because of their speed over open terrain and resistance to heat. Some tribes call them devils because of their horns and because they burn their enemies. Impid tribes' combat tactics usually center on rapid-approach incendiary attacks using both handheld fire weapons and their fire spew ability. -->
  <Impid.description>Stworzeni do życia na pustyni, impidzkie społeczeństwa żyją na wielu rimworldach i suchych martwych światach. Impidzi poruszają się niesamowicie szybko, tolerują wysokie temperatury, i zieją ogniem ze swoich ust. Są mistrzami pustyni, ale ciężko radzą sobie w innych środowiskach. Nie radzą sobie z rolnictwem. Dobrze im idzie walka na odległość, ale na blisko już nie tak dobrze.\n\nCudzoziemcy nazywają ich piaskowymi biegaczami z powodu ich szybkości na otwartej przestrzeni i odporności na ciepło. Niektóre plemiona nazywają ich diabłami z powodu ich rogów i tego, że palą swoich wrogów. Taktyki impidzkich plemion zazwyczaj polega na szybkich atak zapalających, używając ręcznych broni podpalających i swoich specjalnych zdolności.</Impid.description>
  <!-- EN: Made for desert life, impids are very fast, can spew fire from their mouths, and easily tolerate high temperatures. They fight well at range, but in close combat they do little damage. They are terrible with farming, and have weak immune systems. -->
  <Impid.descriptionShort>Stworzeni do życia na pustyni, impidzi są szybcy, zieją ogniem i tolerują wysokie temperatury. Dobrze walczą na odległość, ale nie idzie im w walce na blisko. Nie radzą sobie z rolnictwem, i mają słaby system odpornościowy.</Impid.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: neanderthal -->
  <Neanderthal.label>Neandertalczyk</Neanderthal.label>
  <!-- EN: Neanderthals are stocky, powerfully-built humanoids. Their most salient characteristic is that they are difficult to hurt: They are very resistant to injury, and their strong immune systems protect them from infection. However, without ever having evolved in a complex civilization, they are less adept than baseliner humans at intellectual and social tasks, and their impulsiveness can make them dangerously aggressive.\n\nHomo neanderthalensis was originally an archaic population of hominids that emerged over 200,000 years ago during the Pleistocene epoch. After they were replaced by and merged with humans 30,000 years ago, they were absent for tens of thousands of years until scientists resurrected them from ancient DNA. Neanderthals now survive in sub-societies on some settled planets. On the rimworlds, neanderthal tribes carve out the same existence as their Earth ancestors did so long ago. -->
  <Neanderthal.description>Neandertalczycy to krępi, potężnie zbudowani humanoidzi. Ich najważniejszą cechą jest to, że trudno ich zranić: Są bardzo odporni na obrażenia, a ich silny system odpornościowy chroni ich przed infekcjami. Jednakże, nie rozwinąwszy się nigdy w złożonej cywilizacji, są mniej sprawni niż ludzie bazarowi w zadaniach intelektualnych i społecznych, a ich impulsywność może czynić ich niebezpiecznie agresywnymi.\n\nHomoneandertalczyk był pierwotnie archaiczną populacją hominidów, która pojawiła się ponad 200 000 lat temu podczas epoki plejstocenu. Po tym, jak zostały zastąpione przez ludzi i połączyły się z nimi 30 000 lat temu, były nieobecne przez dziesiątki tysięcy lat, dopóki naukowcy nie wskrzesili ich ze starożytnego DNA. Neandertalczycy przetrwali teraz w subspołeczeństwach na niektórych skolonizowanych planetach. Na rimworldach plemiona neandertalczyków prowadzą taką samą egzystencję, jaką dawno temu prowadzili ich ziemscy przodkowie.</Neanderthal.description>
  <!-- EN: Neanderthals are stocky, powerfully-built humanoids. They are hardy and difficult to injure, and their strong immune systems protect them from infection. However, their minds are less adept at intellectual and social tasks, and their impulsiveness can make them dangerously aggressive. -->
  <Neanderthal.descriptionShort>Neandertalczycy są krępymi, potężnie zbudowanymi humanoidami. Są wytrzymali i trudno ich zranić, a ich silny system odpornościowy chroni ich przed infekcjami. Ich umysły są jednak mniej sprawne w zadaniach intelektualnych i społecznych, a ich impulsywność może czynić ich niebezpiecznie agresywnymi.</Neanderthal.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: pigskin -->
  <Pigskin.label>świnioczłek</Pigskin.label>
  <!-- EN: Pigskins are human-pig hybrids which are capable of two-legged movement, tool use, and speech, but which also retain many pig-like qualities. They are hardy and can eat almost anything without getting sick, but their trotter-shaped hands leave them at a disadvantage when attempting to precisely manipulate tools and objects. They don't see well at a distance, so pigskin gangs usually focus on close-range weapons. They also have a strong taste for explosives.\n\nPigskins were made for their organs. Uncomfortable with the idea of harvesting organs from baseliner humans, a long-gone government merged human DNA into pigs to make the animals produce more easily-transplantable hearts and lungs. They succeeded, but the resulting creatures became more humanlike than anyone anticipated. -->
  <Pigskin.description>Świnioludzie to hybrydy człowieka i świni, które są zdolne do poruszania się na dwóch nogach, używania narzędzi i mowy, ale zachowują wiele cech świniowatych. Są wytrzymałe i mogą zjeść prawie wszystko bez zachorowania, ale ich pstrokate ręce stawiają je w niekorzystnej sytuacji przy próbach precyzyjnego manipulowania narzędziami i przedmiotami. Nie widzą dobrze na odległość, więc gangi świńskie zwykle skupiają się na broni bliskiego zasięgu. Mają również silne upodobanie do materiałów wybuchowych.Świnki zostały stworzone dla swoich organów. Dawny rząd, niezadowolony z idei pobierania organów od ludzi, połączył ludzkie DNA ze świniami, aby zwierzęta produkowały łatwiejsze do przeszczepu serca i płuca. Udało się, ale powstałe w ten sposób stworzenia stały się bardziej podobne do ludzi, niż ktokolwiek się spodziewał.</Pigskin.description>
  <!-- EN: Pigskins are human-pig hybrids. They are hardy and can eat almost anything without getting sick, but their trotter-shaped hands are bad at fine manipulation. They don't see well at a distance, so they usually focus on close-range weapons. They have a strong taste for explosives. -->
  <Pigskin.descriptionShort>Świnioludzie to hybrydy człowieka i świni. Są wytrzymałe i mogą zjeść prawie wszystko bez zachorowania, ale ich pstrokate ręce są kiepskie w drobnych manipulacjach. Nie widzą dobrze na odległość, więc zazwyczaj skupiają się na broni bliskiego zasięgu. Mają silny smak do materiałów wybuchowych.</Pigskin.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: sanguophage -->
  <Sanguophage.label>sanguofag</Sanguophage.label>
  <!-- EN: Sanguophages are a type of archotech-enhanced xenohuman. Powered by archites, their abilities go far beyond normal genetic enhancements. They are mentally adept and preternaturally beautiful. In combat, they can launch deadly spines and heal injured friends. They don't age or die naturally and never suffer from disease or poison. A sanguophage can make a new sanguophage by reimplanting their own xenogerm into a person.\n\nSanguophages must regularly consume hemogen derived from human blood, and they must periodically deathrest for long periods. They're easily destroyed by fire, and slowed down by UV light.\n\nThe first sanguophage appeared thousands of years ago when the lord-explorer Varan-Dur sought to control a hyperintelligent archotech and found himself transformed by it instead. Every sanguophage is descended from him. Since then, sanguophages have often been hunted because of their destabilizing power and their need for blood. Since they can pass for baseliners, many live in hiding among typical humans.\n\nTheir numbers are unknown. Some think they are legends or rare irrelevancies. Some believe sanguophages secretly direct entire human civilizations. The stories speak of eternal lords ruling billions from slate-black space stations, or directing blood sacrifices at conferences in the underlayers of the deepest urbworlds. -->
  <Sanguophage.description>Sanguofagi to rodzaj archatycznie ulepszonych ksenoludzi. Zasilane przez archity, ich zdolności wykraczają daleko poza normalne ulepszenia genetyczne. Są bardzo sprawni umysłowo i niezwykle piękni. W walce potrafią wystrzeliwać śmiercionośne kolce i leczyć rannych przyjaciół. Nie starzeją się i nie umierają w sposób naturalny, a także nie cierpią z powodu chorób czy trucizn. Sanguofag może stworzyć nowego sanguofaga poprzez ponowne wszczepienie własnego ksenozarodka w osobę. Sanguofagi muszą regularnie spożywać hemogen pochodzący z ludzkiej krwi i muszą okresowo odpoczywać przez długi czas. Łatwo je zniszczyć ogniem i spowolnić promieniami UV. Pierwszy sanguofag pojawił się tysiące lat temu, gdy odkrywca Varan-Dur chciał kontrolować hiperinteligentnego archatycznego i zamiast tego został przez niego przekształcony. Każdy sanguofag pochodzi od niego. Od tego czasu sanguofagi są często przedmiotem polowań z powodu ich destabilizującej mocy i zapotrzebowania na krew. Ponieważ mogą uchodzić za zwykłego człowieka, wielu z nich żyje w ukryciu wśród typowych ludzi. Ich liczba jest nieznana. Niektórzy uważają, że są legendami lub rzadkimi nieistotnymi zjawiskami. Niektórzy wierzą, że sanguofagi potajemnie kierują całymi ludzkimi cywilizacjami. Historie mówią o wiecznych władcach rządzących miliardami z czarnych stacji kosmicznych lub kierujących krwawymi ofiarami na konferencjach w podziemiach najgłębszych urbworldów.</Sanguophage.description>
  <!-- EN: Sanguophages are ageless, deathless super-humans powered by archotech-created archites in the bloodstream. They are beautiful and extremely intelligent. They can heal any injury, and never suffer from disease or poison. In combat, they can launch deadly spines and heal injured friends. The price is that sanguophages must consume hemogen derived from human blood to survive, and they must periodically deathrest for long periods. They're easily destroyed by fire, and slowed down by UV light. -->
  <Sanguophage.descriptionShort>Sanguofagi to wieczni, nieśmiertelni super-ludzie zasilani przez stworzone w krwiobiegu archity. Są piękne i niezwykle inteligentne. Potrafią wyleczyć każde obrażenie i nigdy nie cierpią z powodu chorób czy trucizn. W walce mogą wystrzeliwać śmiercionośne kolce i leczyć rannych przyjaciół. Ceną jest to, że sanguofagi, aby przeżyć, muszą spożywać hemogen pochodzący z ludzkiej krwi, a także muszą okresowo umierać na długi czas. Łatwo niszczy je ogień, a spowalnia światło UV.</Sanguophage.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: waster -->
  <Waster.label>śmieciarz</Waster.label>
  <!-- EN: Wasters are aggressive, immune to toxic pollution, almost impervious to disease, and can ingest as much psychite and wake-up drugs as they wish with no ill effects. Their toxin-adapted metabolism means they must consume some form of psychite - usually flake or yayo.\n\nOriginally engineered to prevent resettlement of post-apocalyptic deathworlds, wasters are living area-denial weapons. Waster pirates armed with toxic weapons are the bane of many frontier peoples, both on the rimworlds and in the depths of the urbworld hyperstructures. -->
  <Waster.description>Śmieciarze są agresywni, odporni na toksyczne zanieczyszczenia, prawie niewrażliwi na choroby i mogą spożywać tyle psychitu i wake-up, ile chcą, bez żadnych skutków ubocznych. Ich przystosowany do toksyn metabolizm oznacza, że muszą spożywać jakąś formę psychitu - zwykle flake lub yayo. Pierwotnie stworzone, by zapobiec przesiedleniu do post-apokaliptycznych martwych światów, śmieciarze są żywą bronią masowego rażenia. Piraci uzbrojeni w toksyczne bronie są zmorą wielu ludów frontu, zarówno na rimworldach, jak i w głębi hiperstruktur urbworldów.</Waster.description>
  <!-- EN: Wasters are aggressive, immune to toxic pollution, almost impervious to disease, and can ingest as much psychite and wake-up drugs as they wish with no ill effects. Their toxin-adapted metabolism means they must consume some form of psychite - usually flake or yayo. -->
  <Waster.descriptionShort>Śmieciarze są agresywni, odporni na toksyczne zanieczyszczenia, prawie niewrażliwi na choroby i mogą spożywać tyle psychitu i wake-up, ile chcą, bez żadnych skutków ubocznych. Ich przystosowany do toksyn metabolizm oznacza, że muszą spożywać jakąś formę psychitu - zwykle flake lub yayo.</Waster.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: yttakin -->
  <Yttakin.label>yttakin</Yttakin.label>
  <!-- EN: Yttakin descend from colonists engineered to thrive on ultra-cold planets. Their great size and fur make them hardy in frozen environments. Yttakin share a psychic connection with the wildlife and can summon animals to their side during battles. They are not fast or energetic or precise, but can keep going when others would have collapsed long before.\n\nSince they migrated off their icy birthworld of Yttak, Yttakin settlements live on many planets. Their fur, roaring voices, and aversion to urban living sometimes leads naive outsiders to believe they are simple-minded animals. Quick-minded Yttakin are happy to make good use of such wrong beliefs, whether at the negotiating table or on the battlefield. -->
  <Yttakin.description>Yttakin wywodzą się z kolonistów przystosowanych do życia na bardzo zimnych planetach. Ich wielki rozmiar i futro sprawiają, że są odporni na mroźne środowisko. Yttakin mają psychiczne połączenie z dziką przyrodą i potrafią przywoływać zwierzęta na swoją stronę podczas bitew. Nie są szybcy, energiczni ani precyzyjni, ale potrafią kontynuować, gdy inni załamaliby się już dawno temu. Odkąd wyemigrowali ze swojej lodowej rodowej planety Yttak, osady Yttakin żyją na wielu planetach. Ich futro, ryczące głosy i niechęć do miejskiego życia prowadzą czasem do tego, że naiwni przybysze uważają ich za prostoduszne zwierzęta. Szybko myślący Yttakinowie chętnie wykorzystują takie błędne przekonania, czy to przy stole negocjacyjnym, czy na polu bitwy.</Yttakin.description>
  <!-- EN: Yttakin descend from colonists engineered to thrive on ultra-cold planets. Their great size and fur make them hardy in frozen environments, and they have a unique ability to communicate vocally and psychically with animals. They are not fast or energetic or precise, but can keep going when others would have collapsed long before. -->
  <Yttakin.descriptionShort>Yttakin wywodzą się z kolonistów przystosowanych do życia na bardzo zimnych planetach. Ich wielki rozmiar i futro sprawiają, że są odporni na mroźne środowisko, a także posiadają unikalną zdolność do wokalnej i psychicznej komunikacji ze zwierzętami. Nie są szybcy, energiczni ani precyzyjni, ale potrafią kontynuować, gdy inni załamaliby się już dawno temu.</Yttakin.descriptionShort>
  
</LanguageData>