<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>
    
    <Forbidding.label>Unforbid resources</Forbidding.label>
    <rep>
        <path>Forbidding.helpTexts[0]</path>
        <trans>Colonists will not interact with items marked FORBIDDEN.\n\nForbidden items have a small red X attached. Select a forbidden item and use the controls at the bottom to UNFORBID it.</trans>
    </rep>
    
    <Stockpiles.label>Place stockpile</Stockpiles.label>
    <rep>
        <path>Stockpiles.helpTexts[0]</path>
        <trans>Your colonists need somewhere to store items. Designate a STOCKPILE for them to store things.\n\nFind the stockpile in the ZONES section of the ARCHITECT menu in the lower-left.</trans>
    </rep>
    
    <GrowingFood.label>Place growing zone</GrowingFood.label>
    <rep>
        <path>GrowingFood.helpTexts[0]</path>
        <trans>To grow food, place GROWING ZONES using the Architect menu.\n\nThey can only be placed on fertile ground.</trans>
    </rep>
    
    <EquippingWeapons.label>Equip weapons</EquippingWeapons.label>
    <rep>
        <path>EquippingWeapons.helpTexts[0]</path>
        <trans>Your colonists arrived with some weapons. Equip them!\n\nSelect each colonist and right-click on the weapon you want them to equip.</trans>
    </rep>
    
    <CameraZoom.label>Learn camera zooming</CameraZoom.label>
    <rep>
        <path>CameraZoom.helpTexts[0]</path>
        <trans>Zoom in and out with the MOUSEWHEEL or the T and G keys.</trans>
    </rep>
    
    <WorkTab.label>Configure work settings</WorkTab.label>
    <rep>
        <path>WorkTab.helpTexts[0]</path>
        <trans>You can set each colonist's work settings in the WORK tab at the bottom left of the screen.\n\nThey will always do the highest priority work that they can find.\n\nIf nobody has a certain work type assigned, or if they are busy with higher-priority tasks, it will never get done.</trans>
    </rep>
    
    <TimeControls.label>Learn time controls</TimeControls.label>
    <rep>
        <path>TimeControls.helpTexts[0]</path>
        <trans>You can speed up, slow down, or stop time using the time controls in the bottom right.</trans>
    </rep>
    
    <InfoCard.label>Open info card</InfoCard.label>
    <rep>
        <path>InfoCard.helpTexts[0]</path>
        <trans>The info card shows you detailed statistics about any item, person, or construction.\n\nSelect a person or item and open their info card with the 'i' button on the inspect pane.</trans>
    </rep>
    
    <SpacePause.label>Learn spacebar pause</SpacePause.label>
    <rep>
        <path>SpacePause.helpTexts[0]</path>
        <trans>Hit SPACE to pause or unpause the game.\n\nYou can give orders while paused.\n\nRemember this - if things get hectic, just hit SPACE!</trans>
    </rep>
    
    <StorageTab.label>Learn storage tab</StorageTab.label>
    <rep>
        <path>StorageTab.helpTexts[0]</path>
        <trans>You can configure stockpiles and storage buildings by selecting them and opening the STORAGE TAB above the bottom-left inspector pane.</trans>
    </rep>
    
    <MedicalOperations.label>Learn medical operations</MedicalOperations.label>
    <rep>
        <path>MedicalOperations.helpTexts[0]</path>
        <trans>To assign a medical operation, like organ harvesting or prosthetics installation, open a colonist's HEALTH tab, then switch to the OPERATIONS sub-tab.</trans>
    </rep>
    
    <HomeArea.label>Learn home area</HomeArea.label>
    <rep>
        <path>HomeArea.helpTexts[0]</path>
        <trans>The HOME AREA tells your colonists which area to clean and where to extinguish fires.\n\nDefine the HOME AREA with the Zones category under the Architect menu.</trans>
    </rep>
    
    <RightClickClearLetter.label>Learn clearing letters with right-click</RightClickClearLetter.label>
    <rep>
        <path>RightClickClearLetter.helpTexts[0]</path>
        <trans>You can quickly dismiss incoming letters by right-clicking them.</trans>
    </rep>
    
    <BuildOrbitalTradeBeacon.label>Build orbital trade beacon</BuildOrbitalTradeBeacon.label>
    <rep>
        <path>BuildOrbitalTradeBeacon.helpTexts[0]</path>
        <trans>To send items or silver to orbital traders, you must build an ORBITAL TRADE BEACON and place a stockpile of items near it.</trans>
    </rep>
    
    <SetGrowingZonePlant.label>Learn growing zone config</SetGrowingZonePlant.label>
    <rep>
        <path>SetGrowingZonePlant.helpTexts[0]</path>
        <trans>You can set what to plant in a growing zone. You can even grow trees!\n\nJust select the growing zone, open the Growing tab, and click the 'plant' button.</trans>
    </rep>
    
    <PrisonerTab.label>Learn prisoner tab</PrisonerTab.label>
    <rep>
        <path>PrisonerTab.helpTexts[0]</path>
        <trans>Look in a prisoner's 'Prisoner' tab to set how they'll be treated.\n\nYou'll need a colonist with the Warden work to take care of the prisoner.</trans>
    </rep>
    
    <StoragePriority.label>Learn to set storage priorities</StoragePriority.label>
    <rep>
        <path>StoragePriority.helpTexts[0]</path>
        <trans>You can change the PRIORITY of storage. Colonists will fill higher-priority storage first.</trans>
    </rep>
    
    <HistoryTab.label>Learn history tab</HistoryTab.label>
    <rep>
        <path>HistoryTab.helpTexts[0]</path>
        <trans>You can see a record of your colony's fortunes over time in the HISTORY tab at the bottom of the screen.</trans>
    </rep>
    
</LanguageData>
