<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>
    
    <CraftingSpot.label>crafting spot</CraftingSpot.label>
    <CraftingSpot.description>A place for crafting simple things like shivs or bows.</CraftingSpot.description>
    
    <NutrientPasteDispenser.label>Dozownik pasty odżywczej</NutrientPasteDispenser.label>
    <NutrientPasteDispenser.description>Syntetyzuje pastę odżywczą z organicznych składników. Pochłania mniej składników i czasu niż inne metody produkowania pożywienia, ale nikt nie lubi jeść pasty odżywczej. Przyjmuje surowe jedzenie oprócz niejadalnych roślin (np. siana).</NutrientPasteDispenser.description>
    
    <Hopper.label>Pojemnik</Hopper.label>
    <Hopper.description>Przechowuje zasoby używane przez maszyny, takie jak dozownik pasty odżywczej.</Hopper.description>
    
    <TableButcher.label>Stół rzeźniczy</TableButcher.label>
    <TableButcher.description>Ciężki stół wykorzystywany do ćwiartowania stworzeń i pozyskiwania surowego mięsa oraz skór.</TableButcher.description>
    
    <ElectricTailoringBench.label>electric tailoring bench</ElectricTailoringBench.label>
    <ElectricTailoringBench.description>A workbench with a sewing machine for rapid tailoring of clothes. Can work without electricity at 40% of normal speed.</ElectricTailoringBench.description>
    
    <HandTailoringBench.label>hand-tailoring bench</HandTailoringBench.label>
    <HandTailoringBench.description>A workbench for tailoring clothes by hand. Works at 40% of the speed of an electric tailoring bench.</HandTailoringBench.description>
    
    <ElectricSmithy.label>electric smithy</ElectricSmithy.label>
    <ElectricSmithy.description>An electric-powered station equipped for smithing non-mechanical weapons and tools.</ElectricSmithy.description>
    
    <FueledSmithy.label>fueled smithy</FueledSmithy.label>
    <FueledSmithy.description>A wood-fueled station equipped for smithing non-mechanical weapons and tools.</FueledSmithy.description>
    
    <TableSculpting.label>Warsztat rzeźbiarza</TableSculpting.label>
    <TableSculpting.description>Stół warsztatowy wyposażony w narzędzia do rzeźby artystycznej.</TableSculpting.description>
    
    <TableMachining.label>Stół warsztatowy</TableMachining.label>
    <TableMachining.description>Stół wraz z narzędziami służący do składania i rozbierania cyborgów, jak i do produkcji pocisków moździerza.</TableMachining.description>
    
    <ElectricStove.label>electric stove</ElectricStove.label>
    <ElectricStove.description>An electrically-powered stove with an attached countertop for preparing meals.</ElectricStove.description>
    
    <FueledStove.label>fueled stove</FueledStove.label>
    <FueledStove.description>A simple wood-fueled stove with an attached countertop for preparing meals.</FueledStove.description>
    
    <TableStonecutter.label>Stół kamieniarski</TableStonecutter.label>
    <TableStonecutter.description>Ciężki stół służący do wycinania cegieł ze skalnych odłamków.</TableStonecutter.description>
    
    <Brewery.label>Browar</Brewery.label>
    <Brewery.description>Miejsce wyposażone we wszystkie narzędzia do wytwarzania piwa.</Brewery.description>
    
    <ElectricSmelter.label>Przetwórnia metalu</ElectricSmelter.label>
    <ElectricSmelter.description>Odzyskuje użyteczny metal ze stopionych metalowych odpadków. Zużywa duże ilości energii.</ElectricSmelter.description>
    
    <ComponentAssemblyBench.label>component assembly bench</ComponentAssemblyBench.label>
    <ComponentAssemblyBench.description>A workbench equipped with advanced tools for producing components from simpler materials.</ComponentAssemblyBench.description>
    
    <SimpleResearchBench.label>simple research bench</SimpleResearchBench.label>
    <SimpleResearchBench.description>A simple bench with writing implements and low-tech scientific tools. Researchers work here to discover new things.</SimpleResearchBench.description>
    
    <HiTechResearchBench.label>hi-tech research bench</HiTechResearchBench.label>
    <HiTechResearchBench.description>A high-tech bench with computers and electronic measurement equipment. Research is sped up by the high-tech tools. Requires power.</HiTechResearchBench.description>
    
    <ElectricCrematorium.label>electric crematorium</ElectricCrematorium.label>
    <ElectricCrematorium.description>Cremates corpses. Electrically-powered.</ElectricCrematorium.description>
    
    <HydroponicsBasin.label>Stół bezglebowy</HydroponicsBasin.label>
    <HydroponicsBasin.description>Służy do bezglebowego hodowania roślin. Stół wymaga prądu do działania, bez którego rośliny umrą.</HydroponicsBasin.description>
    
</LanguageData>
