<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>
    
    <!--=============== Pure stuffs: Basics ====================-->
    
    <Silver.label>silver</Silver.label>
    <Silver.description>This metal is mostly used as a commodity currency. It can also be used for making attractive decorations.</Silver.description>
    
    <Gold.label>gold</Gold.label>
    <Gold.description>The most seductive metal of them all. Millions have died in attempting to feed the endless human thirst for gold. This soft metal is little use on its own, but is strikingly beautiful and very rare.</Gold.description>
    
    <Steel.label>steel</Steel.label>
    <Steel.description>An iron-carbon metal alloy used for building structures, tools, and weapons.</Steel.description>
    
    <Plasteel.label>plasteel</Plasteel.label>
    <Plasteel.description>Advanced spacer tech structural material. Plasteel is extremely strong due to its unique molecular structure.</Plasteel.description>
    
    <WoodLog.label>wood</WoodLog.label>
    <WoodLog.description>Wood from trees or other fibrous plants. Useful for building structures, weapons, and even simple prosthetics. A raw stick of wood can be used as a weapon in a pinch.</WoodLog.description>
    
    <Uranium.label>uranium</Uranium.label>
    <Uranium.description>An extremely hard, dense metal. While it is best known for its use powering nuclear reactors, its physical properties also make it excellent in some roles as a tool, weapon, or armor.</Uranium.description>
    
    <!--=============== Pure stuffs: Fabric, leather, etc  ====================-->
    
    <Cloth.label>cloth</Cloth.label>
    <Cloth.description>Cloth woven from organic fibers.</Cloth.description>
    
    <Synthread.label>synthread</Synthread.label>
    <Synthread.description>Spacer-tech synthetic fabric designed for making ordinary clothes. It is soft, light, strong, and insulates well.</Synthread.description>
    
    <DevilstrandCloth.label>devilstrand</DevilstrandCloth.label>
    <DevilstrandCloth.description>Fabric spun from microfibers extracted from silk-producing Devilstrand mushrooms. Very tough, but insulates no better than cloth.</DevilstrandCloth.description>
    
    <Hyperweave.label>hyperweave</Hyperweave.label>
    <Hyperweave.description>High-tech nano-fibers woven into sheets. It is somewhat heavy, but is incredibly difficult to break. The secrets of its production are known only to the most advanced glitterworld cultures.</Hyperweave.description>
    
    <!--=================== Plant products ===============-->
    
    <RawHops.label>hops</RawHops.label>
    <RawHops.description>Raw hops. A flavoring and preserving agent that is necessary for making beer.</RawHops.description>
    
    <RawPotatoes.label>potatoes</RawPotatoes.label>
    <RawPotatoes.description>Raw potatoes.</RawPotatoes.description>
    
    <RawCorn.label>corn</RawCorn.label>
    <RawCorn.description>Raw corn. Nice to eat, even when raw.</RawCorn.description>
    
    <RawRice.label>rice</RawRice.label>
    <RawRice.description>Raw rice.</RawRice.description>
    
    <RawBerries.label>berries</RawBerries.label>
    <RawBerries.description>Assorted berries. Nice to eat, even when raw.</RawBerries.description>
    
    <RawAgave.label>agave fruit</RawAgave.label>
    <RawAgave.description>Raw agave fruit.</RawAgave.description>
    
    <!--=============== Medicine ====================-->
    
    <HerbalMedicine.label>herbal medicine</HerbalMedicine.label>
    <HerbalMedicine.description>A pack of herbal concoctions typically extracted from the xerigium plant. Less potent than industrial pharmaceuticals.</HerbalMedicine.description>
    
    <Medicine.label>medicine</Medicine.label>
    <Medicine.description>Medical staff use these supplies to heal the wounded.</Medicine.description>
    
    <GlitterworldMedicine.label>glitterworld medicine</GlitterworldMedicine.label>
    <GlitterworldMedicine.description>Advanced medical supplies from a high-tech glitterworld.</GlitterworldMedicine.description>
    
    <!--=============== Shells ====================-->
    
    <ArtilleryShell.label>artillery shell</ArtilleryShell.label>
    <ArtilleryShell.description>Fired from artillery cannons.</ArtilleryShell.description>
    
</LanguageData>
