<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>
    
    <!-- ============================ Animals ========================== -->
    
    <Muffalo.label>muffalo</Muffalo.label>
    <Muffalo.description>A large herding herbivore descended from buffalo and adapted for some exotic environment. Peaceful unless disturbed.</Muffalo.description>
    
    <Deer.label>deer</Deer.label>
    <Deer.description>A medium-sized herding herbivore. Generally peaceful unless disturbed.</Deer.description>
    
    <Squirrel.label>squirrel</Squirrel.label>
    <Squirrel.description>One of the many hardy, versatile rodent species that follows humankind everywhere it spreads.</Squirrel.description>
    
    <WildBoar.label>wild boar</WildBoar.label>
    <WildBoar.description>Although considered impure by some cultures, this hairy ancestor of the domesticated pig is prized for the gamey flavor of its meat.</WildBoar.description>
    
    <Rhinoceros.label>rhinoceros</Rhinoceros.label>
    <Rhinoceros.description>This large land mammal is typically quite peaceful, but it will not hesitate to charge with its horn to fend off trespassers.</Rhinoceros.description>
    
    <Dromedary.label>dromedary</Dromedary.label>
    <Dromedary.description>Adapted to survival in arid environments, this distant cousin of the horse can go nearly a week without water.</Dromedary.description>
    
    <Boomrat.label>boomrat</Boomrat.label>
    <Boomrat.description>Either by deliberate genetic weaponization, or as an unusual defense mechanism, these rodent-like creatures create a powerful fire-starting explosion when killed.</Boomrat.description>
    
    <Iguana.label>iguana</Iguana.label>
    <Iguana.description>These large lizards normally feed on plant matter. However, when angered, their tough hide and sharp claws make them quite dangerous.</Iguana.description>
    
    <Megascarab.label>megascarab</Megascarab.label>
    <Megascarab.description>A large, genetically-engineered beetle. Once the worker caste of an artifical ecosystem of insectoids designed to fight mechanoid invasions, it is now usually seen without its deadlier insectoid cousins. Still, its size and hard shell make it dangerous when it attacks.</Megascarab.description>
    
    <Tortoise.label>tortoise</Tortoise.label>
    <Tortoise.description>This heavily armored land-dwelling reptile is known for its slow moving speed and surprisingly vicious bite.</Tortoise.description>
    
    <Cobra.label>cobra</Cobra.label>
    <Cobra.description>A large snake. Cobras can be highly aggressive if provoked - it's better to stay away from these creatures.</Cobra.description>
    
    <Monkey.label>monkey</Monkey.label>
    <Monkey.description>This monkey can use its curly tail to grab on to branches, leaving its hands free to do other things.</Monkey.description>
    
</LanguageData>
